ALEJANDRO GONZÁLEZ

me@algorodev.com · 648183931 Valencia, Spain · 9 June, 1997

Tech-enthusiast with +4 years of experience as a programmer with quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Experience of working with tight deadlines, under time pressure while ensuring quality and with agile methodologies.

I'm always curious to learn more about technologies and any kind of art, I'm a passionate about music, films and sports.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2022 - NOW

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, MERCEDES-BENZ

I've honed my skills in writing high-quality code, emphasizing clean code practices, adhering to SOLID principles, and implementing design patterns. I'm also well-versed in working within agile methodologies. One of my primary challenges has been adapting to the pressure of working on a product that undergoes constant change.

HTML5 - React - Vite - TypeScript - Sass - MaterialUI - Express - NodeJS - Swagger - Storybook - Jest - Vitest - Cypress - PostreSQL - Azure - Git - Github - SonarQube - SCRUM

JUN 2020 - FEB 2023

CEO & FOUNDER, ENCODERAPE

I've acquired the ability to maintain composure and patience when dealing with clients, along with effective task and long-term project management skills. Additionally, I've gained experience in tasks such as deployments, networking, and systems management. One of my primary challenges has been adapting to the pressure of client demands, knowing that months of work, meetings, and coordination need to be organized efficiently.

HTML5 - React - Angular - TypeScript - Sass - Express - NodeJS - NestJS - Swagger - Storybook - Jest - Cypress - PostreSQL - MongoDB - AWS - Git - Bitbucket - SonarQube - SCRUM

MAR 2021 - OCT 2021

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, CAPGEMINI

I've gained expertise in designing a monolithic architecture with shared libraries and a strong emphasis on code reusability. Additionally, I've developed excellent client communication and presentation skills. My experience extends to both technical architecture and effective client interaction.

HTML5 - Angular - TypeScript - Sass - Angular Material - Nx - NestJS - Swagger - Storybook - Jest - Cypress - PostreSQL - MongoDB - Azure - AWS - Git - SonarQube - SCRUM

MAR 2021 - OCT 2021

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, CAPGEMINI

I've learned the intricacies of building a product from scratch, encompassing architecture, technology choices, and more. Additionally, I've acquired skills in effectively managing a small team. My most significant challenge was successfully leading a small team while preparing and developing the product

HTML5 - React - TypeScript - Sass - TailwindCSS - Jest - Laravel - PHP - Git - Gitlab - SCRUM

SEP 2020 - MAR 2021

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, VINFOVAL

I've acquired the skills to write high-quality code, emphasizing clean code principles and adhering to the SOLID principles. Additionally, I've become proficient in working within agile methodologies. One of my primary challenges was transitioning to a professional work environment, where the stakes are high, and errors carry significant consequences in a production setting.

HTML5 - Angular - TypeScript - Sass - Bootstrap - Jest - DevExtreme - SmartAdmin - Git - Azure - SonarQube - SCRUM

JUN 2019 - JUL 2022

FREELANCE

I've acquired the skill of delivering high-quality and maintainable applications. I've also become proficient in tasks such as deployments, networking, and systems management. My most significant challenge has been adapting to the pressure of client expectations, where the organization of months of work and meetings becomes paramount.

HTML5 - Angular – TypeScript – Sass – Express - NodeJS - Jest – Cypress – MongoDB – Git – Github

EDUCATION

AUG 2020

BOOTCAMP FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, GEEKSHUB ACADEMY

- Learn technologies and tools used by active professionals.
- Learn the flow of creating a web application and be able to implement it.
- Know the work methodologies used in the companies where you will join
- Create a complete professional project portfolio to show all the knowledge acquired throughout the process.
- Practice your soft skills to complete your professional profile and thus make easier your entry into the labor market.

JUN 2019

SENIOR TECHNICIAN IN CROSS-PLATFORM APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT, CIEEP PROGRESA

- Configure and operate computer systems, adapting the logical configuration of the system according to the needs of use and the criteria established.
- Apply techniques and procedures related to safety in systems, services and applications, complying with the security plan.
- Manage databases, interpreting their logical design and verifying data integrity, consistency, security and accessibility.
- Manage development environments by adapting their configuration in each case to enable application development and deployment.
- Develop cross-platform applications with access to databases using languages, libraries and tools suitable to specifications.
- Integrate graphic content and multimedia components in cross-platform applications, using specific tools and meeting established requirements.
- Develop applications for phones, PDAs and other mobile devices using specific development techniques and environments.
- Develop multi process and multi-thread applications using specific programming techniques and libraries.
- Participate in the implementation of ERP-CRM systems evaluating the usefulness of each of its modules.
- Manage the information stored in ERP-CRM systems ensuring its integrity.

JUN 2017

TECHNICIAN IN MICRO COMPUTER SYSTEM AND NETWORKS, CIEEP PROGRESA

- Install and configure basic and application software, wired, wireless or mixed local networks and connected to public networks.
- Install, configure, and maintain multi-user services, applications, and shared devices in a local network environment.
- Assemble and configure computers and peripherals.
- Determine the logistics associated with the installation, configuration and maintenance of micro informatics systems.
- Diagnose dysfunctions in micro informatics systems and networks through functional tests.
- Redesign the wiring and electronics of local networks in small environments and their connection to large area networks.
- Execute established data recovery procedures and applications in case of data failure and loss in the system.

CERTIFICATION

NOV 2016

CAMBRIDGE B1

DEC 2023

SAFE 5 PRACTITIONER CERTIFICATION

DEC 2023

SAFE 5 PRACTITIONER CERTIFICATION